ARIEL JONATHAN ROFFÉ

RESEARCHER & SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



EDUCATION

Universidad de Buenos Aires: Philosophy (PhD) | 2016 - 2020

Universidad de Buenos Aires: Philosophy (undergrad) | 2010 - 2016

- Final grade average: 9.61

Universidad de Buenos Aires: Common Basic Cycle & Business management | 2008 - 2010

- Switched to Philosophy in 2010.

Escuela Técnica ORT: Techinal bacherlor specialized in informatics | 2002 - 2007

- Graduated with honors.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Universidad de Buenos Aires | Professor (JTP): 2015 - current

- Courses Taught: Logic, Methodology of Science, Philosophy of Science, Programming for Philosophers, Git for Philosophers, among others.

CONICET | Post-doctoral fellow: 2021 - 2024

CONICET | Doctoral fellow: 2016 - 2021

Universidad de Buenos Aires | Stimulus research scholarship: 2014 - 2016

Roffé Propiedades | Real Estate Agent: 2010 - 2014

RESEARCH

Selected publications

- Roffé, A. J. & Pailos, F. (in press). Translating Metainferences Into Formulae: Satisfaction Operators and Sequent Calculi. *Australasian Journal of Logic*.
- Roffé, A. J. (2020). Dynamic Homology and Circularity in Cladistic Analysis. Biology & Philosophy.
- Roffé, A. J. (2019). Drift as Constitutive: Conclusions From a Formal Reconstruction of Population Genetics. History and Philosophy of the Life Sciences.
- Roffé, A. J. (2019). Reconstructor: A computer program that uses three-valued logics to represent lack of information in empirical scientific contexts. *Journal of Applied Non-Classical Logics*.
- Roffé, A. J. (2018). Contemporary Perspectives on the Meaning, Roles, and Implications of Chance in Evolution. *Science & Education*.

ABOUT ME

PhD Philosophy researcher from Argentina. I have published in Q1 journals, in topics ranging from mathematical logic to the philosophy of biology. 6+ years of experience teaching university-level courses.

I am passionate about software development. I've created tools used by universities worldwide. Contributed in and created open-source projects with 80+ stars on GitHub.

TECH STACK

★★★★★ Expert:

Python, Django, HTML/CSS, Git

★★★★ Advanced:

JavaScript, Phaser 3

★★★ Familiar:

Rust, Julia, Docker

LANGUAGES

- Spanish (Native speaker)
- English (Proficient)
- Portuguese (Basic understanding)

CONTACT

- arielroffe@filo.uba.ar







SELECTED SOFTWARE PROJECTS

(See all at my personal website)

Ariel Roffé's Quest (my personal website)

- Written in JavaScript with the Phaser 3 Game engine.
- Open source. 80+ stars on GitHub. Got to the #1 spot on HackerNews.
- 19k+ visits only in March 2022.

CIyNE cinema database

- Django + PostgreSQL + Docker project.
- Worked with a group of researchers that had compiled a set of Excel sheets with argentinean movies from 1900 onwards.
- My job was to design an SQL database, move the data from the Excel sheets, and show the information while imitating filo.uba.ar site's aesthetics.

TAUT / logics

- Mathematical logic learning tools written in Python + Brython + Bootstrap.
- TAUT is a website that contains randomly-generated, self-correcting logic exercises
- Around 35k visits since inception. Has been used in logic courses at various universities worldwide (Argentina, Australia, Germany, Perú, United States, etc.)
- logics is the open-source Python framework behind TAUT.

Cladule

- Academic congress automatic scheduling tool written in Python + NumPy + Numba.
- Working prototype. Used for generating the schedule of the AFHIC 2018 congress (~350 expositions in 5 days).
- Uses phylogenetic algorithms (inspired by biological systematics) to find optimal schedules for conferences with many simultaneous expositions, and different kinds of constraints (no author superposition, thematic coherence, time/day requests by authors, etc.)









